原创翻译 双语字幕
最新连载海外影视资讯
请登陆 yysub.net
仅供交流学习 禁止商用盈利
翻 译     贝七  小涵同学han  肥嘟嘟
翻 译     易碎的绝对  纸鹤
校 对     肥嘟嘟
时间轴   DA  树
后 期     渔夫
总 监     Elena777
杰瑞快乐牧场
水果硬糖
给  宝贝
Here, baby.
小茹
Rue?
宝贝  你得喝水  好吗
Baby, I need, I need you to drink this, okay?
喝吧  喝吧
Come on, come on.
就喝一口  宝贝  求你了
Let's just take a sip, baby, please.
要我帮你剥吗
Do you need help with that?
我扶住你了
I got you.
知道我喜欢医院哪一点吗
You know what I like about hospitals?
快到了  加油
We're almost there. Come on.
他们不用知道你是不是个好人
They don't need to know how good of a person you are
就会照顾你
in order to take care of you.
加油
Come on.
他们不需要知道你脑子里在想什么
They don't need to know what's going on in your head
就会在你胳膊上缠好绷带
before they wrap a bandage around your arm.
加油
Come on.
这样的人很少见
People like that are rare.
那个医生让我妈妈联系了一家
The doctor put my mom in touch with a rehab,
下周初可能有空床位的戒毒所
who might have an open bed early next week.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
让我坚持住
Told me to stay strong.
好了  好了  好了
Okay, okay, okay.
我妈也属于那种少见的人
My mom is one of those rare people,
但也许是因为她是我妈
but maybe that's 'cause she's my mom.
另外  她在教堂长大
She also grew up in the church.
随便你说基督徒怎样
And say what you want about Christians.
至少他们相信宽恕
At least they believe in forgiveness.
我不记得任何我对我妈说过的话
I don't remember everything I said to my mom.
没事的 小茹
It's okay, Rue.
没事的
It's okay.
我多想说那些都不是真心的
I wish I could say I didn't mean any of it.
那是真话吗  至少我想过
Is that actually true? I mean, I thought it.
感受过  也说出口了
I felt it... I said it.
我知道大多数人会说
I'm sure most people would say
这世上没我更好
the world would be a better place without me.
我不否认
I don't disagree.
其实我从记事起
In fact, I've been trying to leave it
就在试着离开这个世界
for as long as I can remember.
阿里也是那种少见的人之一
Ali is also one of those rare people.
奇怪的是
The strange thing is,
我打赌大多数人会一致评价他说
I bet most people would say the same thing about him.
"他就是个打老婆的瘾君子"
"He's just a fuckin' crackhead wife-beater."
我敢说他女儿这么说过
I bet his daughter said that.
连我都多少说过
Even I kinda said that.
我后悔那样
That I regret.
真的很后悔
Really fucking regret.
但如果坦诚地说我是谁
But if I'm being honest about who I am...
我是撒谎精  是贼
I'm a liar, a thief.
我暴力  虐待  操纵人心
I'm violent, abusive, manipulative.
冷
It's cold.
冷  妈  妈  冷
It's cold, Mom. Mom, it's cold.
小茹  你得退烧  宝贝  好吗
Rue, you have to break your fever, baby, okay?
好吗  来
Okay? Come on.
即使我今天戒毒了
And even if I got clean today,
没人会忘记我吸毒时的创伤
no one would forget the trauma of me not being clean.
该死
Shit.
但我真的后悔对阿里说那些话
But I really regret what I said to Ali.
将某人的一生删减到一刻
Reducing someone's life to a moment...
丑陋的一刻
an ugly moment.
为那一刻而惩罚他们
And punishing them for it.
那是警察做的事
That's what cops do.
也是每个人都会做的事
It's actually what everyone does.
你如果不了解我  也会对我做这样的事
It's what you would do to me if you didn't know me.
总之  我应该打给阿里道歉
Anyway, I should call Ali and apologize.
喂
Hello.
阿里
Ali?
是我  小茹
It's, um, it's Rue.
有事吗  小茹
What do you want, Rue?
我只是想打给你  告诉你
I just wanted to, uh, call you and tell you that, um...
我想打给你
I just wanted to call you
告诉你我很抱歉说了那些话
and tell you that I'm sorry for what I said.
我真的很后悔
and I really regret it.
我...  我不该说那些话
I just-- I never should've said that.
小茹
Rue.
-我很抱歉  对不起  -小茹
- And I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - Rue!
听我说
Listen to me.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
真的
You do?
I do.
你怎么知道我是真心的
How do you know that I mean it?
因为这一刻迟早会来
Because the hour is certain to come.
我们必须从容原谅
So we must forgive graciously.
谢谢你
Thank you.
迷醉
第二季  第六集
你看着虚弱得像个林黛玉
You look like a cat coughed your ass up.
阿里说只有让他
Ali said he would only stop by
给我们全家做饭他才愿意来
if he could cook dinner for the whole family.
谢谢你们邀请我
Aw, thanks for having me.
-你好  -你好
- Oh, hi. - Hi.
我是阿里  很高兴认识你
I'm Ali. Nice to meet you.
-你是小茹的担保人  -是的
- You're Rue's sponsor? - Uh... I am.
不如说说  你这会儿在干嘛
A better question is, uh, what're you doin' right now?
没干嘛
Nothing.
-想帮我做饭吗  -我可以帮忙
- Wanna help me cook? - Uh, I can help.
算了算了  别让你戒断期间
Nah, nah, you keep your stank
拉稀的屁股把我的菜熏臭了
withdrawal diarrhea-ass all away from my food.
-你要不要告诉他...  -不  不
- Oh, you wanna tell him about-- - No, no!
-我觉得你应该说  -不  不
- I think you should. - No, no, no!
我认真的  你威胁到我们健康了
Hey, yo, yo! I'm serious. You're a health hazard.
-回房去  -好吧  我去  谢了  抱歉
- In the other room. - Okay, dang. Thank you. Sorry.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
拜拜  你也拜拜
Bye-bye? Bye-bye to you, too.
我知道你肯定洗过她的臭屁股
I know you probably been washin' that ass.
她们知道我没说错
They know I'm right.
没错
Exactly.
我觉得她今天好多了
I think she's doin' better today.
比起小茹的艰难
For as tough as it's been on Rue,
我知道这对你来说更不容易
I'm sure it's been harder on you.
把这些番茄切块
Dice these tomatoes.
你可以生她的气
It's okay to be angry at her.
我觉得那样帮不到任何人
I'm not sure that helps anyone.
我看未必
Ah, well, oh, I... tend to disagree.
我觉得那对你有好处
I think it would actually be good for you.
怎么说
How?
生她的气错不在你
You're not wrong to be angry at her.
这种事很伤人
That shit hurts.
很不公平
It's unfair.
你不该承受这些
You don't deserve it.
我没事
I'm fine.
真的
I am.
我没说我不信你
I didn't say I didn't believe you.
内特还不知道凯茜和麦迪的事
Now, Nate didn't know what happened with Cassie and Maddy
因为他锻炼时手机静音
because when he exercises, he puts his phone on silent.
凯茜: 我需要马上和你谈谈
38个来自凯茜的未接电话
讽刺的是内特今早醒来
The irony was Nate woke up that morning
感觉好极了
feeling fantastic.
因为在和他爸斗了18年后
Because after an 18-year dick-swinging contest with his dad...
内特终于赢了
Nate had finally won.
他妈妈似乎应对自如
His mom seemed to be handling it well.
而另一边他哥却...
His brother on the other hand...
她在乐什么呢
Fuck is she so happy about?
不怎么样
not so well.
让他担心的
It wasn't the 38 missed calls
不是凯茜的38个未接来电
from Cassie that concerned him.
而是麦迪一个电话都没打
It was the fact that there were zero calls from Maddy.
内特那么爱麦迪的其中一个原因是
Part of the reason Nate loved Maddy as much as he did
她的忠诚
is because she was loyal.
也是这一点把他吓到腿软
But it's also what scared the living shit out of him.
惹毛她的人都会被弄死
If anyone crossed her, she'd bury them.
现在他真的惹毛她了
And he had now really fucking crossed her.
内特对麦迪要做什么
And there was no doubt in Nate's mind what Maddy
了如指掌
was about to do.
当一个孩子在校园里枪杀别人
You know when a kid shoots up a school
别人去采访他父母的时候
and they go to interview the parents,
那对父母说  "我们不知道
and the parents are like, "We had no idea.
他看着挺正常的"
He seemed, like, totally normal."
所有观众心想  "你这个白痴"
And everyone watching is like, "You're a fucking idiot."
我对凯茜就是这种感受
That's how I feel, but with Cassie.
听着  我从不信任她
Look, I never trusted her.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
因为她看上去像
Because she seems like the kind of person
会睡你男友的那种人
who would fuck your boyfriend.
我觉得我真的想杀了她
I think I actually wanna murder her.
我懂
I get it.
不  是真的
No, like, actually...
计划谋杀  付诸行动
plan a murder and carry it out.
我懂
I get it.
像那种震惊全国的可怕谋杀案
Like a grisly murder. One that shocks the nation.
这就不好懂了
I think that's more than understandable.
内特呢
What about Nate?
我有几个主意
I have a few ideas.
不是吧
No!
-好阴暗  -你们准备好点单了吗
- That's dark-sided. - Are you two ready to order?
不
No.
她还在打电话  我们过几分钟再点
she's just on the phone. We'll just be a couple minutes.
我们希望顾客在餐桌上不要使用手机
We prefer customers not use phones at the tables.
-不不不  -我能理解
- No, no, no. - I can understand.
那我过会儿再来
I will circle back.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
她是个贱人  对
She's a cunt, yeah.
好吧  再见  爱你  好的
All right, bye. Love you. Okay.
抱歉  我想着咱们还没问好呢
Sorry... I j-- We haven't said hello yet,
所以我决定
so I just figured
像平常那样来迎接你
I would greet you like I normally greet you.
对不起
Oh, sorry.
麦迪在经历一些事
Maddy's going through this thing. You know?
当然
Sure.
-我懂  很尴尬  -是啊
- I get it. It's awkward. - Yeah.
-我们在这儿干什么  -约会
- So, what are we doing here? - Goin' on a date.
是吗
Yeah?
因为在电话里你说得好像
'Cause on the phone you just kind of made it sound
是什么紧急事件一样
like, like it was an emergency.
-是吗  -是的
- Did I? - Yeah.
-不  -你问我能不能取消彩排
-No. -Like, you asked if I could cancel rehearsal.
我  我想说  我一直...
I, um, I mean, well, I've--
我一直...
I've...
在思考...  我们和我们的关系
been thinking... about us and, and our relationship,
以及...
and, um... um...
我得了...  脑紊乱
I have a... brain disorder.
什么
What?
我就说到这儿了
That's the rest of the sentence.
我很疑惑
Um, I'm confused.
我觉得已经是晚期了
I think it's terminal.
你思考了很久我们的关系
Y-Y-You've been thinking a lot about our relationship
因为你得了晚期脑紊乱
because you have a, you have a terminal brain disorder?
是啊  我一直在思考...
Yeah, I just, like, keep thinking, like,
所有医院探视  以及...
all the hospital visits, and...
我可能还得辍学
maybe, I'll have to get out of school,
待在家
stay home, you know,
享受仅剩不多的时间
with the little time I have left.
你得的晚期脑紊乱叫什么
What is this terminal brain disorder called?
不  不  不
No, no, no.
你会去谷歌上查  然后仔细阅读
'Cause you're gonna google it, and then read about it,
我就会在你脸上看到那副表情
and I'm just gonna see it on your face.
我感觉你在对我撒谎
I feel like you're l-lying to me.
撒谎得了晚期脑紊乱吗
Lying about a terminal brain disorder?
太可怕了吧
That's sick.
说实话  事实上你认为
A-And to be honest, the fact that you think
我会对你撒这样严重的谎
I would even lie about something that awful
就意味着我们的关系中存在很大问题
means there's a big problem in this relationship,
就像
which is, like,
我一开始想说的那样
literally what I was trying to say in the beginning.
不  不  一开始
No, no. In the beginning,
我就感觉你要跟我分手了
I feel like you started to break up with me,
然后你转移话题告诉我
and then, you pivoted to telling me that
你得了晚期脑疾
you got, like, a terminal brain illness,
现在我又感觉你在利用我的怀疑
and now, I feel like you're using my skepticism
当作和我分手的理由
as, like, a reason to break up with me.
那是你的感觉
That's your experience.
不  我觉得...  事实就是这样
No, I think... that's the experience.
是你对这件事的主观臆测
It's your experience of the experience--
凯特  如果你不想跟我在一起
Kat, you don't wanna be in a relationship with me.
我能理解  你可以直说
And I get it. If it's okay, just say it.
只要你有诚实表态的勇气
Just have, like, the courage to actually be honest
因为现在你的所作所为
'cause what you're doin' right now,
真的让人感觉很糟糕
it's just, like-- feels like shit.
我知道  我...
I knew it. I-- Wow.
我简直难以置信
Wow, I can't believe this.
你真的要跟我分手
You're literally trying to break up with me.
不  我只是在帮你说出你想说的
No, I'm, I'm trying to help you say what you wanna say.
这是什么
Is this some sort of, like,
你在恶臭男讨论区
manipulation tactic you learned
学到的操纵技巧吗
on some fucking incel Reddit forum?
老天  这就是你这种男人的问题
God, this is the problem with guys like you.
我告诉你我病了
I tell you I'm sick,
而你直接忽略我的经历
and you just dismiss my experience.
操纵我  告诉我怎样去感受
Yeah, you just gaslight me, tell me how to feel
只因我达不到你的期望
all because I don't meet your expectations.
好吧  你说得对
All right, well, you're right.
你没有达到我的期望
You didn't live up to my expectations
因为我的确期望你至少能诚实
because I did expect you to at least be honest.
-我很诚实  -行吧
- I am being honest. - All right,
我甚至觉得这话你自己都不信
I don't even think you believe that,
但这都是次要的
but, you know, that's besides the point
因为我觉得我们该分手了
'cause I think we need to break up.
这我倒没料到
Wow, wow. I didn't see that one coming.
我也没有
I didn't either.
再见
Bye!
小莱
Lex...
亲爱的  把这些放后院藏到灌木里
Hon, take these in the back and hide 'em in the bushes.
你真觉得她会捅自己吗
You really think she's gonna stab herself?
你姐姐非常冲动...  是的
Your sister's very emotional... Yes.
-真的吗  -藏到灌木里  就现在
- Really? - In the bushes, now.
快去
Go!
快点
Hurry!
折断树枝来掩盖灌木丛中
It was at some point while breaking branches off a tree
那一篮子刀具的
in order to camouflage a bucket
某个时刻
of kitchen knives in a bush...
莱克茜开始
that Lexi started to have
重新思考是否要把她的剧本搬上舞台
second thoughts about putting on her play.
你知道...
Well, you know what...
最应该写进你剧本里的
what you should put in the play...
是我在派对上暴揍内特那次
that time I beat Nate's ass at that party.
才不是  天呐
No! Oh god.
我也不知道  凯茜现在状态不太好
I don't know. Cassie isn't doing too well.
我担心...
I'm worried that...
她会看到这个剧  然后  她会...
she's gonna see the play, and then, she's gonna...
崩溃
freak out.
是的  我想说...
Yeah, I mean...
每个人的感情都会受到伤害
everybody gets their feelings hurt. You know?
对
Yeah.
有些人...
Some people...
有些人的感情有时就是需要受伤
some people need to get their feelings hurt sometimes.
是啊  我...
Yeah... I--
感觉是我人生第一次
It's, like, the first time in my life
为自己做一些事
I'm doing something for myself.
我去
Shit.
这个剧本背后的想法是什么
What exactly is... the idea behind the play?
我不知道  就...  就是
I don't know, it's... it's, like,
关于一群好姐妹
about a group of girlfriends
她们...
who sort of...
一起长大又分道扬镳
grow up and grow apart.
我去  所以就像
Damn, so it's kinda like, uh,
-《伴我同行》那种感觉  -是的  没错
- "Stand By Me" Vibes. - Yes, exactly!
-我超爱那部电影  就是那样  -是啊
- I love that movie. That's... exactly it. - Hell yeah.
别说了  那部电影我看了大概五十遍
Come on now. I've watched that film, like, 50 times.
-真的吗  -那是我的最爱  信我
- Have you really? - That's my shit, come on.
实际上  我姥姥有这部电影的影碟
In fact, my, my grandma has it on DVD, you know?
要看吗
Should we watch it?
莱克茜需要清静一下
Lexi needed a break.
凯茜  我能用厕所吗
Cassie... can I use the bathroom?
不行
No.
我是内特
Yo, this is Nate.
我正忙  哔声后请留言
I'm busy. Leave a message at the beep.
我是内特  我正忙
Yo, this is Nate. I'm busy.
哔声后请留言
Leave a message at the beep.
不管你做什么
Whatever you do,
不要跟任何高中认识的人结婚
don't marry anyone you meet in high school.
我认真的  我过去也很有趣
I mean it. I used to be fun.
知道你不相信
And I know you don't believe me,
-但我那时很辣  -不  我相信你
- but I was fuckin' hot. - No, I believe you.
本可以得到任何我想要的东西
Yeah, well, could've had anything I wanted.
结果我却...  爱上了你爸爸
Then I just... fell in love with your dad.
-我很高兴他现在走了  -是啊
- Well, I'm very happy he's gone. - Yeah.
帮我个忙  别对我撒气
Do me a favor. Just... don't take your anger out on me.
我为何要对你生气
Why would I be angry at you?
因为你易怒
'Cause you're an angry guy.
不  我对爸爸很生气
No, I was angry at Dad.
这跟易怒很不一样
That's very different than, you know, being angry.
好吧  随便你怎么说
Okay... Whatever you say.
而且我认为在我发怒的时候
And I feel like when I was angry,
都有很正当的理由
I had a pretty good reason to be angry.
好吧  听着  我不是说发怒的人
Okay, look, I'm not, I'm not saying angry people
没有理由发怒
don't have a reason to be angry.
好吗  你讨厌你爸
Right? You hated your father.
这跟其他理由一样说得通
That's as good a reason as any.
对  但我指的是
Yeah, but that's my point.
我的怒气是针对他
My anger was directed toward him.
不是针对其他人
It's not just towards anyone.
那我就不知道了
Yeah, I don't know about that.
不  我的怒气是有特定对象的
No, it's not. It's fuckin' specific.
好  听着
Okay, look...
我们能轻松地聊会儿天吗
can we just have a nice time?
好吗
Yeah?
-好  -好的  谢谢
- Yeah. - Okay, thank you.
还得再来一瓶
Need another bottle.
我不是坏人
I'm not the bad guy.
所有人都看着我  好像我是坏人似的
Everyone keeps looking at me like I'm the bad guy,
但我不是坏人
but I'm not the bad guy!
-你也不是好人  -对  肯定不是
- Well, you're not the good guy. - Yeah, that's for sure.
所有人都认为内特和麦迪还在一起时
Everyone thinks that I was hooking up with Nate
我就跟他勾搭上了
when he and Maddy were still together,
但这不准确  时间上并不重合
but that's not accurate. There was no crossover.
凯茜  拜托  请冷静一点
Cassie, please, just a little bit of peace, please.
但小茹说得好像
But Rue made it sound like
我们一直在勾勾搭搭
we were just hooking up the entire time,
但我绝不会这样对我爱的人
but I would never do that to someone I love.
好吧  我认为这不是无懈可击的辩解
Yeah, I don't think that's a real airtight defense.
这是事实
It's the truth!
凯茜  你快把我逼疯了
Oh, Cassie, you're driving me nuts!
你做过什么是一回事
It's one thing to do what you did,
装作完全无辜又是另一回事
and it's another thing to pretend you're all innocent,
-这不是什么大事  -我只是指出事实
- and it's no big deal. - I'm just pointing out the facts.
-我是在指出原则  -什么原则
- Well, I'm pointing out the principle. - What principle?
"别碰闺蜜男朋友"原则
The "Don't fuck your best friend's boyfriend" principle.
这就是我要跟你说的  妈
That is what I am trying to tell you, Mom!
他们当时不是男女朋友  天啊
They weren't boyfriend and girlfriend, god!
我不在乎
I don't care!
我只想安静地看一小时
I just wanna watch my "Millionaire Matchmaker"
《百万爱情介绍所》
in peace for one hour,
就一小时
one goddamn hour!
靠
Fuck!
你还在和那个金发姑娘见面吗
You, uh, you still seein' that, that, that blonde girl?
为什么这么问
Why?
因为相比麦迪我更喜欢她
'Cause I prefer her to Maddy.
你运气不错
Well, you're in luck.
所以你们在约会吗
So, so you're dating?
不  我是说
No, I just mean
麦迪永远不会再跟我说话了
Maddy's never gonna fuckin' talk to me again.
-那太好了  -走着瞧吧
- Oh, well, that's good. - Well, we'll see.
我  我之前很怕你把她肚子搞大
I was, I was just terrified you were gonna get her pregnant.
谁  麦迪吗
Who? Maddy?
她是那种会留着孩子只为刁难你的人
She's the type that would keep it just to spite you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我无法想象她当妈
Can't really picture her being a mom.
天啊  我可以
Ooh, man, I could.
尤其当这意味着她有机会
Especially if it meant she had the chance
一辈子坑死你
to screw you over for the rest of her life.
好吧  她没怀孕
Yeah, well, she's not fuckin' pregnant,
她也永远不会再跟我说话
and she's never gonna talk to me again.
那个金发姑娘呢
So... what about the blonde girl?
-一言难尽  -怎么了
- Oh, it's complicated. - Why?
她是麦迪最好的朋友
Um, she's Maddy's best friend.
我去
Shit.
谁才是那个贱人
Who's the cunt now?
你记得她说那话的时候吗
Do you remember when she said that?
-是的  我记得  -天啊
- Yes, I do remember. - Oh my god.
我知道这么说不对
I know it's not the right thing to say...
但你在那之后抓住她
but when you grabbed her after that, and you, like,
把她拽走  我就想"这才是我儿子"
pulled her ass off, I was thinkin', "That's my boy."
好吗  "为妈妈出头"
Huh? "Stickin' up for his mama."
天呐  我去
Oh my gosh. Shit.
-是啊  那么做太疯狂了  -我知道
- Yeah, it was a pretty insane thing to do. - I know, well,
你不必掐住她的脖子
you know, you didn't have to go so far as to choke her.
-我没掐她脖子  -好吧
- I didn't choke her. - Mmm.
-妈  他们撤销了指控  -好的
- Mom, they dropped the charges. - Okay.
-我没掐她脖子  -听着
- I didn't fuckin' choke her. - Look...
在那一刻  我也想掐死那姑娘
at that moment, I, I wanted to choke the girl, too.
行  但我要说的是我没掐她  妈
Yeah, but my point is I didn't fucking choke her, Mom.
知道了
Okay!
别那么生气到最后要掐我脖子了
Don't get so upset that ya end up chokin' me.
因为我不会撤销指控
'Cause I won't drop the charges.
我会清理门户
I'll fuckin' clean house.
抱歉
Sorry.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我想死
I just wanna die!
开瓶器割不开的
Well, a corkscrew ain't gonna cut it.
不...
No...
我早就说了
I told you.
我不明白  我以为你讨厌内特
I don't understand. I thought you hated Nate.
我那时不了解他
When I didn't know him.
你和他已经认识很久了
You've literally known him forever.
和我现在了解的不同
Not like I do now.
等等  这就是你背叛菲兹克的原因吗
Wait, is this why you ratted on Fezco?
不是
No.
天呐  所以你才那么做吗
Oh my god. That's why you did it?
-不是  -这就是你为什么会那么说吗
- No! - That's why you said something?
-因为你当时在和他上床  -我没有
- 'Cause you were sleeping with him? - No, I wasn't!
真的吗  你们什么时候开始上床的
Oh really? When did you start sleeping together?
我不...  我不知道具体日期
Uh... I, I don't, I don't know the exact date.
好吧  是跨年派对之前还是之后
Okay, well, was it before or after New Year's?
我不知道
I don't know!
好吧  但对你这么痴迷于
Okay, but for someone who's so obsessed with
时间管理的人来说  我不信
windows of time, I find that hard to believe.
天啊  莱克茜  你让我感觉更糟了
God, Lexi, you are making me feel worse!
你知道菲兹克为什么要那么做吗
Do you even know why Fezco did what he did?
-不  难道你知道  -对
- No, do you?! - Yeah, I do.
那就告诉我
Then tell me.
我会不告诉你的  因为你会告诉内特
No, I'm not gonna tell you because you'll tell Nate.
-我不相信你  -没人相信我
- I don't fuckin' trust you. - No one does!
对  因为你爱上了一个
Yeah, 'cause you fell in love with someone
多年来一直取笑你的人  太可悲了
who spent years making fun of you. It's sad.
你知道爸背着你搞外遇吗
Did you know Dad was cheating on you?
你知道吗
Did you?
不知道
No.
我  我根本不相信
I don't, I don't believe that for a second
因为他来这里时
because when he came in here
一边怒气冲冲地大吼说
and he was ranting and raving about
他是个男人  一边标记自己的地盘
bein' a man, and markin' his territory--
我根本不知道他在说什么
I don't know, whatever the fuck he was talking about.
我看了看艾伦  再看了看你
I looked at Aaron and I looked at you,
天啊  你和他的反应
and, boy, was there a difference
截然不同
in his response and your response.
因为艾伦是个蠢货
It's because Aaron is a fucking idiot.
好吧  他就是个蠢货
Okay, he is, isn't he?
这太糟了  笑死我了
That's terrible. I'm laughing.
知道吗
You know what?
我想买台健身器
I think I'm gonna buy a Peloton.
-对  我要开始约会  -你是个酒鬼
- Yeah, I am gonna start dating. - You're a drunk.
怎么  你不想要继父吗
Mm, what? You don't want a stepfather?
-妈  闭嘴  -不要吗
- Mom, shut up. - No? Ooh, ooh!
你的同龄人怎么样  那会很有趣
What about one who's your age? That'd be fun.
闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
你幼稚得像个青少年
You're acting like a fuckin' teenager.
-我的老天啊  -真厉害
- Jesus fuckin' Christ. - Wow!
为什么  你为什么
Why is it, why is it that you only have
只继承了你爸的缺点
the bad qualities of your father,
-一点优点都没继承呢  -好吧
- and none of the good qualities? - Okay.
行  所以卡尔现在成圣人了
Right, so Cal, Cal's a fuckin' saint now.
不  我...  我没这么说
No. That's, that's, that's not what I said.
你就是这么说的
That's literally what you fuckin' said.
不  我没有  我只是...
No, it's not. I just--
他有严重的性格缺陷  不知为什么
He's deeply flawed, and somehow...
我们却以某种方式
somehow, some way, we
培养出一个性格缺陷更严重的孩子
raised a child who's even more deeply flawed.
你有想过吗  你有想过...
Do you ever wonder about that? Do you just like--
到底哪里出了错  你想过吗
What went wrong? Do you ever think about that?
当然没有  你不会想
No, of course, you don't
因为你那个蠢货爹
because your fuckin' dumb-ass dad
不相信心理治疗  所以
didn't believe in therapy, so...
你不可能自我反省  只是...
self-reflection's off the table. It's just--
只是我不理解
It's just a mystery to me.
因为你从前是多么可爱的孩子
'Cause you were such a sweet little baby.
我记得你过去晚上常来我们卧室
I remember you used to come to our bedroom at night,
你会问我
and you would, you would ask me
入睡前想不想
if I wanted anything to drink,
喝点什么  有时我会说
you know, before bed, and sometimes I'd say,
"是的  我想喝杯水"
"Yeah," you know, "I want a glass of water,"
就想看看你是否真的会去倒水
just to see if you'd, if you'd do it, if you meant it,
而你去倒了
and you did.
你会把水端来  好吗
Hm, you'd bring it up, right?
把水放在床头柜上
You'd put it on the nightstand,
然后轻轻亲我一下
and then, you'd give me a little kiss,
告诉我你爱我
and you'd tell me you loved me.
然后你看向你爸
Then you'd look over at your dad,
告诉他你也爱他
and... you'd tell him you loved him, too,
但没亲他
but without the kiss.
然后  我不知道  差不多
And then... I don't know, somewhere, like, around...
八九岁时  你变抑郁了
eight or nine, you just, you-you darkened.
你还记得那些年吗
Do you remember those years?
-不记得了  -天啊  我曾问你爸说
- Not really, no. - God, I used to ask your dad,
"他被棒球砸中头了吗
I was like, "Did a baseball hit him in the head?
"他得了脑震荡吗  出什么事了
"Did he get a concussion? Did something happen?
我  我不明白"
I just-- I don't understand."
简直判若两人  我发誓...
It was such a drastic change, and I, I swear--
有什么意义  说这些有什么意义
What's the fucking point? What's the point of all this?
听着  我只是想搞清
Look, I'm just-- I'm just tryin' to figure out
事情怎么最终变成这个样子  仅此而已
how things ended up the way they ended up. That's all.
我觉得你话里有话
I feel like you're tryin' to say something without sayin' it.
我没有
I-I'm not.
忘记我...
Just... forget I--
谁说内特是坏人来着  小茹吗
Who said Nate was a bad person? Rue?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
因为如果我们想谈论人
'Cause if we wanna talk about people,
-那就谈谈小茹吧  -小茹是个好女孩
- let's talk about Rue. - Rue's a good girl.
我就不是吗
And I'm not?
我没说你不是好女孩
I didn't say you're not a good girl.
小茹过得很艰难
Rue's had a very hard life.
也没我和莱克茜艰难
Not harder than my life or Lexi's life.
-不一样  -行吧
- It's different. - Right.
她爸死了  我们的爸爸没联系了
Her dad died and ours just stopped calling.
我不知道哪个更糟
I don't know which is worse.
如果你不是个没自尊的
And if you weren't such a fucking loser
窝囊废
with no self-respect,
你就放弃她了
you'd drop her 'cause she
-因为她对你糟透了  -够了  够了
- treats you like shit. - Enough! Enough!
怎么  我不能这么说她
What, I can't say it to her,
你俩却可以这么说我
but you two can say it to me?!
我从没说过你没有自尊
I never said you didn't have any self-respect!
不用你说  我他妈感觉到了
You don't have to! I can fuckin' feel it!
真该给她驱个邪
Oh, she needs a fucking exorcism.
事实是  内特根本不在乎
The truth was, Nate didn't give a shit
他爸会怎么样
about what would happen to his dad.
但他确实
He did, however,
很关心他爸的生意会怎样
care about what happened to his dad's business
因为最终都会成为他的生意
because, eventually, that would become Nate's business.
虽然他不怎么了解房地产
And while he didn't know much about real estate...
但他知道
he did know there wasn't
恋童癖建的房子没什么市场
much of a market for homes built by a pedophile.
享受成为一家之主的感觉吧
恋童癖儿子建的房子也一样
or the son of a pedophile.
虽然严格说来  他不是恋童癖
Even though, technically, he wasn't a pedophile,
但也不可能大声争辩
but it's not like you could argue that out loud.
此时  茱尔丝在家
Meanwhile, Jules was at home.
她再也没和埃利奥特说话  自从...
And she hadn't talked to Elliot since...
告诉你吧
You know what?
其实  我不想谈茱尔丝和埃利奥特
Actually, I don't want to talk about Jules and Elliot.
去他们的  我们谈回麦迪
Fuck them. Let's go back to Maddy.
然后  有两个王嘘[任天堂旗下角色]
Then, there are two King Boo's,
然后  有三个王嘘
and then, three King Boo's.
麦迪不只是生内特和凯茜的气
Maddy wasn't just angry about Nate and Cassie.
她还很沮丧  心碎
She was also depressed and heartbroken.
凯茜一直在安慰她
All the times that Cassie consoled her,
安抚她  假装陪着她
comforted her, pretended to be there for her...
都不是真的
none of it was real.
都是错觉
It was all an illusion.
萨曼莎: 15分钟内到家
-今晚怎么样  -很棒
- How was your night? - It was nice.
我有段时间没见闺蜜们了
I hadn't seen my girlfriends in a while,
能聊点毫无意义
so it was good to catch up
但有趣的东西挺好的
on all the meaningless, fun bullshit.
西奥和我打了两个半小时游戏
Well, Theo and I played two and a half hours of video games,
他告诉我他很喜欢恶魔
and then, he told me about how he loves demons,
我睡觉时  他们会偷走我的心
and that when I sleep, they're gonna steal my heart.
这孩子比较怪
He's a nut.
我们应该喝个烂醉  然后去游泳
Feel like we should get drunk and go for a swim.
好
Okay.
麦迪不想告诉萨曼莎
Maddy didn't wanna tell Samantha
内特和凯茜的事
what had happened with Nate and Cassie.
但两杯酒下肚
But after two glasses of wine...
她就把他俩的事跟她说了
she told her what had happened with Nate and Cassie.
-太糟糕了  -对吧
- God, that's horrible. - Right?
-你想听更糟糕的事吗  -什么
- You want to hear something more horrible? - What?
我上大学时
When I was in college,
也对我一个好朋友做了这种事
I kind of did the same thing to one of my best friends.
-你说你是我  -不
- You mean you were me? - No.
那就没那么糟了  我是她
No, that'd be less horrible. I, I was her.
别告诉我  我还挺喜欢你的
Don't tell me that. I like you.
-千万别和我说  -知道知道
- Please don't tell me that. - Yeah, I know, I know.
你上了你闺蜜的男朋友
You fucked one of your girlfriend's boyfriends?
很多次
Yeah, multiple times.
你对好几个闺蜜都这么做了
You did this to multiple girlfriends?
不  天啊  只有一个
No! Jesus. Just one.
很多次
Yeah... many times.
好吧  你们有多要好
Okay, but how close were you?
-别这样对我  -对不起
- No, don't do this to me. - I know. I'm sorry.
为什么
Why?
因为他在错误的时间
Because he gave me just the right
给了我恰到好处的关注
amount of attention at the wrong time.
太难过了
That is so depressing.
我在高中  大学和20多岁时
I was a fucking mess in high school...
都一团糟
in college, and in my 20s.
一想到世上有人愿意和我安顿下来
The idea that there was ever anyone in the world
并和我结婚
who... would want to settle down and marry me
我就很震惊
was a complete shock to me.
-你在说谎  -我没有
- You're lying. - No. I'm not.
我真的是那种
I was, literally,
每个人和他们母亲常提的女孩
the girl that everyone and their mothers used to say,
"没有人会安顿下来娶她
"No one would ever settle down and marry her,
上帝保佑娶她的人"
and God-help whoever did."
他们为什么这么说
Why would they say that?
因为我一团糟
Because I was messy.
我喜欢吵架
Oh, and I loved to fight.
我不是一团糟  但我喜欢吵架
See, I'm not a mess, but I do love a fight.
-这样最好  -完全被低估了
- Oh, it's the best. - Totally underrated.
长远来看  没那么重要
In the long run, not so much,
-但在当下  -酷毙了
- but in the moment? - It's fucking amazing.
太棒了
Oh, it's so good.
-但这就是我  -是吗
- But... I mean, that's just who I am. - Yeah?
我以前也这么认为  直到遇见塞巴斯蒂安
I used to think that's who I was, too, until I met Sebastian.
你不吵架了
You don't fight?
不怎么吵
Not really, no.
-真的吗  -嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
我觉得我的大脑没法那样
I just don't think my brain is wired that way.
如果你四十多岁还和这种男人约会
If you are still dating guys like this in your 40s,
我们的对话会大不一样
we'd be having a very different conversation,
但你才十八岁  谁在乎啊
but you're 18 years old. Who gives a shit?
你和你朋友和好了吗
Did you and your friend ever make up?
没有  她再也没和我说话
God no. She never spoke to me again.
导演
罗伯·莱纳
编剧
雷纳尔多·吉迪恩  布鲁斯·A·埃文斯
天啊
Oh god.
太伤感了
It's so sad.
眼睛里好像进东西了
Think I got somethin' in my fuckin' eye.
♪大地一片漆黑♪
♪ And the land is dark ♪
♪我们只能看见那光亮♪
♪ Is the only light we'll see ♪
♪不  我不会害怕♪
♪ No, I won't be afraid ♪
♪我不会害怕♪
♪ Oh, I won't be afraid ♪
♪只要你站在♪
♪ Just as long as you stand ♪
♪在我身旁♪
♪ Stand by me ♪
♪亲爱的  亲爱的  在我身旁♪
♪ So darlin', darlin', stand by me ♪
♪在我身旁♪
♪ Oh, stand by me ♪
♪站在♪
♪ Oh, stand ♪
♪在我身旁  在我身旁♪
♪ Stand by me, stand by me ♪
♪如果我们仰望的天空♪
♪ If the sky that we look upon ♪
♪摇摇欲坠♪
♪ Should tumble and fall ♪
♪或者山脉崩塌入海♪
♪ Or the mountains should crumble to the sea ♪
♪我不会哭  我不会哭♪
♪ I won't cry, I won't cry ♪
♪我不会掉眼泪♪
♪ No, I won't shed a tear ♪
♪只要你站在♪
♪ Just as long as you stand ♪
♪在我身旁♪
♪ Stand by me ♪
♪亲爱的  亲爱的  在我身旁♪
♪ And darlin', darlin', stand by me ♪
♪在我身旁♪
♪ Oh, stand by me ♪
♪现在站在♪
♪ Woah, stand now ♪
♪在我身旁♪
♪ Stand by me ♪
费伊  过来
Faye! Come here.
他妈的快点
Hurry the fuck up!
-你在干什么  -我得和你谈谈
- What are you doing? - I gotta talk to you.
你为什么在巷子里
Why are you in the alley?
然后条子敲我的门
And then, so the fucking cops knock on my door,
-问各种问题  -什么问题
- askin' all kinds of questions. - What questions?
-有关"老鼠"的问题  -你说什么了
- Questions about Mouse. - What did you say?
什么也没说  但第二天我在街上走
Nothing. But then, the next day I was walking,
我口袋里有些奥施康定
and I'm like-- I had a couple OCs in my pocket,
他们就跑过来  说些疯话
and they just ran up talkin' all kinds of crazy shit.
你要坐牢了  我们知道是你杀了"老鼠"
You know, "You're gonna go to prison. We know you killed Mouse."
我说  我没杀"老鼠"
I was like, "I, I didn't kill Mouse."
你跟他们合作了
Are you cooperating?
当然没有
Hell no.
宝贝  他们已经盯上小菲和"烟缸弟"了
Babe, they already had their sights set on fuckin' Fez and Ash.
所以你在和警方合作
So, you are cooperating with the police.
我不知道这个词对不对
I do not know if that is the right word,
但我是在帮他们
all right, but I'm helping 'em out.
他们肯定之前就盯上他们了
Okay, they definitely had their sights set on them beforehand,
所以我什么也没做
so I didn't set anything into motion.
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, baby,
我很快就会过来
and I'm gonna be coming over soon,
和你谈些事
and I'm gonna be talkin' about some things,
你别插手
and I need you to stay the fuck out of it.
在下雨
Oh, hey, it's raining.
我要去洗个澡
I'm gonna take a shower.
很难做啊
This shit go hard.
但说真的
But for real though, if,
如果你的剧本像《伴我同行》一样
if your play is anything like "Stand By Me,"
你肯定没问题的
you're not gonna have no problems.
笑一个  你入镜了
你在干什么
What are you doing?
别担心  我不是来道歉的
Don't worry. I'm not here to apologize.
你能想象我坐在这拿把枪
Can you imagine if I was sitting here with a gun
逼你接受我的道歉吗
forcing you to accept my apology?
-你吓到我了  -是啊
- You're scaring me. - Yeah...
说到点上了
It's kinda the point.
我爱你  我爱你  内特
I love you. I love you, Nate.
内特  我爱你
Nate... I love you.
我比世上的任何人都了解你
I know you better than anyone in this world.
我羞辱了你
I humiliated you.
我们结束了
It's over.
你觉得我爸为什么喜欢拍性爱录像
Why do you think my dad likes to film himself fucking?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你敢信那是茱尔丝吗
Can you believe it was Jules?
我要那张碟
I'm gonna need that disc now.
我没有
I don't have it.
好
Okay.
行
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
别这样  内特
Stop it, Nate.
住手  内特  停
Stop, Nate, stop.
求你停下
Please, please stop.
求你住手  求你了
Please, stop it, stop it, please.
求你停下
Please, stop it.
停停停
Stop, stop, stop.
在...  在我包里
It's in, it's in my purse.
碟在我包里  在我包里
It's in my purse. It's in my purse.
对不起
Hey, I'm sorry.
对不起  我...
I'm sorry. I was--
-我开玩笑...  -别碰我
- I was jok-- - Don't touch me!
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
枪里没有子弹
There's no bullets in the gun.
再见
Goodbye.
未知来电
-喂  -听着  我知道你可能不想跟我谈
- Hello? - Look, I know you probably don't wanna talk to me,
但我快到你家外面了
but I'm about to be outside your house,
我真的得和你谈谈
and I really need to speak to you.
我不在乎
I don't care.
内特: 是关于我爸
和你
内特: 我只是希望你能保护自己
内特: 我在前门外
不用  谢谢
No, thank you.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
我知道你恨我
I know you hate me.
我做了很多坏事
I've done a lot of shitty things,
但这不是其中一个
but, um... no, this isn't one of 'em.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
首先  向你道歉
First... to apologize.
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
我知道  但你对第二件事肯定感兴趣
I know, but you are gonna be interested in the second thing.
对你来说不幸的是
Unfortunately for you,
你得先听我的道歉
you're gonna have to hear my apology first.
对不起
I'm sorry...
为我对你所做的一切感到抱歉
for everything that I've done to you.
你不该承受这些
You didn't deserve it.
我...  我当时是想保护
I was, uh... I was tryin' to protect somebody
一个不值得被保护的人
that didn't deserve to be protected.
如果可以的话我愿意收回一切
If I could take it all back, I would.
但事已至此
But... I did what I did.
我从这张碟里发现
I found out about you and my dad from, um...
你和我爸的事
from this disc.
他偷偷录下了每一次约炮
Yeah, he, uh, he secretly records every encounter he has,
说实话  从我记事起
and, you know, he's been doin' it, well...
他就一直这么干
well, honestly, as long as I can remember.
我从他那偷了这张碟  他崩溃了
I stole it from him, and he had a, he had a mental breakdown,
他搬了出去
and he moved out of the house,
所以我想我可以...
so I thought that I would, uh--
我想把它给你
I thought I'd give it to you, and, you know, you can
凭你处置
do with it as you please.
-所以那里有摄像头  -对
- So, there was a camera? - Yes.
你看过了吗
And you've seen it?
是的
Yeah.
-很多人看过吗  -不  没有
- Have a lot of people seen it? - No, no.
他知道你把它给我吗
Does he know you're giving this to me?
不知道  不然他会杀了我
No... No. He would fuckin' kill me.
这是唯一一份吗  还是...
Is this, like, the only copy, or...
有其他的备份
is it other, other places?
据我所知就这一份
I mean, it's the only one that I know of, yeah.
你为什么要给我
Why are you giving this to me?
说实话  答案很简单  也挺傻的
Honestly, the answer is too stupid and simple.
我觉得我们对这件事保密比较好
I think it's better if we just keep it a mystery.
什么  你现在成好人了吗
What, did you become, like, a good person?
绝对不是  不
Absolutely not, no.
你真该看看我为了拿到它做了什么
I mean, you should've seen what I had to do to get it.
我出来的时候袖子里藏了把美工刀
I came out here with a box cutter in my sleeve.
以防出现
You know, in, in case there was a chance
我要割你喉的情况
I might have to slit your throat.
我就是这么不相信你
That's how little I trust you.
谢谢
Well, uh, thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
-我要走了  -好的
- Um, I'm gonna go. - Okay.
不管怎样
Hey, um... for what it's worth...
我说的一切都是真的
everything I ever said was true.
我也是
Same here.
-喂  -打包行李
- Hello? - Hey, pack a suitcase.
我十分钟后到你家
I'll be at your place in 10.
-你可以住我家  -好
- You can stay at my house. - Okay.
爱你
Love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
内特: 到了
我为你毁了我的人生
I ruined my entire life for you.
-你多大了  -22
- How old are you? - Uh, 22.
私心里...
Selfishly...
我希望你留下
I hope you stay.
张大点
Wider.
张大点  很好
Wider... There you go.
很好
That's it.
真乖
Good girl.
小茹  小茹
So, Rue, Rue.
你觉得自己坠入谷底了吗
So, you think you hit rock bottom?
是的
Yes.
好吧  我知道
Um... okay, uh, I know...
自己要向很多人道歉
that I have a lot of apologizing to do.
我懂
Uh... I get that.
所以我觉得我要...
So, I just figured that I'd, you know...
去戒毒所戒毒  整理好自己
go to rehab, get clean, you know, sort my shit out, and, um...
然后回来道歉
then come back, and... apologize.
所以你想戒毒吗
So you wanna get clean?
-对  -好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
你对此有什么感觉
How do you feel about that?
如果是真的  那挺好
If it's real, then great.
-是真的  -你之前也这么说过
- It is. - You've said that before.
吉雅  别这样
Gia, come on.
她不信她有什么问题吗
What's wrong with her not believin' her?
我觉得她需要我们所有人的支持  好吗
I think she needs all of our support. Right?
我不觉得这是支持的问题
I don't think it's a question of support.
当你让别人一次又一次失望
When you've let someone down again and again,
失去一点信心无可厚非
I think it's fair to lose a little faith.
你怎么看呢
I mean, what do you think?
觉得她会戒毒吗
You think she'll get clean?
我不知道
I don't know.
她说有百分之五左右的机会  对吗
She said it's like a five percent chance, right?
差不多吧
Somethin' like that.
那有什么希望呢
Where's the hope in that?
这就要靠小茹自己去找了
The hope... is what Rue has to find.
没错  小菜一碟
Yeah... piece of cake.
让小茹做自己
Let Rue be Rue--
也给予小女儿足够的爱
and shower that little one with love.
她一直在等
She's been waitin' on it.
介意我晚上和你睡吗
You mind if I sleep in your bed tonight?
当然不了  来吧
Yeah, yeah, for sure. Come on.
我感觉对你的生活一无所知了
I feel like I don't know anything about your life anymore.
等你回来我会告诉你的
I'll tell you when you get back.
好
Okay.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Night.
喂
Hello?
对  是我
Yes, this is her.
对  我女儿  她17岁
Yeah, my daughter. She's 17 years old.
鸦片剂  海...  海洛因
I think opiates, hero-heroin.
我觉得主要就是鸦片剂
I think mainly just opiates.
我大概四天前带她去了急诊室
Well, I t-took her to the emergency room about four days ago,
医生给了她什么来缓解戒断反应
and... the doctor gave her somethin' to help with the withdrawal.
但我希望能尽快让她入住
But I was hopin' to bring her in as soon as possible.
但她需要住院
But she needs to be in an inpatient hospital.
你不了解我女儿  好吗
You don't understand my daughter, okay?
她是瘾君子  她要自杀
She's a drug addict, okay? And she's gonna kill herself.
拜托  我求你了  好吗
Please, I am beggin' you, please, okay?
她需要住院  而不只是脱瘾治疗
She needs to be in an inpatient, not just the detox.
她需要回到戒毒所
She needs to be put back into rehab.
不  不要  求你听我说
No, don't. Please listen to me.
我了解我的女儿  她会自杀的
I know my daughter. She is going to kill herself.
请你不要这样做  求你了
Please don't do this, please. I'm begging.
拜托  不要这么对我们  求你了
Please, don't do this to us. Don't do this to us, please!
我女儿要自杀啊
My daughter's gonna kill herself.
lf.